Daniel Burgess

Full Stack Developer

Phone: 0434 869 784

Email: dan-burgess@hotmail.com

Location: Adelaide SA DOB: 10/10/1993

Portfolio and Links: github.com/DBurgess93 danielburgessportfolio.herokuapp.com linkedin.com/in/daniel-burgess-668176186/

Professional Summary

Ambitious, reliable and functionality first Full-Stack Developer. Looking to engage in a new team environment and apply programming skills, as well as build upon knowledge base in the interest of ongoing improvement.

Graduate of Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp, skilled in both front-end and back-end programming languages/frameworks, as well as databases to build fully functional web applications with a focus on user experience and optimal performance. Portfolio includes both team and individual projects taken from initial design to deployment, using tools to track progress and organise team workflow.

Previous work includes 8 years in sales and customer relations roles, 6 years in heavily team-based roles, experience in teaching workplace processes, leading small teams and working autonomously.

Previous employees would endorse for having a great attitude, being a hard worker, a people person and someone who is curious and eager to learn.

Summary of Skills

Technical Skills

- JavaScript
- React.JS
- Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL
- Firebase
- HTML5
- css/scss
- Bootstrap
- Figma
- REST API and web scraping
- Web hosting using Heroku
- GitHub
- WordPress CMS
- Shopify
- Trello Workflow and Task Tracking

Soft Skills

- Great communication/People Person
- · Organisation
- Collaborative Mindset
- Leadership Qualities
- Adaptability
- · Problem solving
- Curiosity
- Highly Personable

Education

WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE 2022

Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp - Bali

DIPLOMA OF REMEDIAL MASSAGE 2015

Endeavour College of Natural Health

HIGH SCHOOL GRADUATE - 2011

Nuriootpa High School

Top Projects

Deepwork

- A Web-app designed to help students track how they spend their study time, analyse their data for a better understanding of their studying habits and motivate them to reach a state of deep focus.
- Tech-stack: Ruby on Rails, SASS, HTML, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Figma.

<u>De-fit</u>

- A Web-app built to help bring together those who are in need of a fitness space and those who have one to share.
- Tech-stack: Ruby on Rails, SASS, HTML, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Figma.

IGNFY (I've Got News for You)

- A Web-app built for users to showcase to their friends and followers the "breaking news" that's happening in their lives.
- Tech-stack: ReactJS, Typescript, Firebase, CSS, HTML, JavaScript.

Freelance Web Development

 Design and build various websites for small start-ups as part of The RED Group initiative. The RED Group help people with disabilities start their own Micro Enterprise. I work closely with The Red Group and the enterprise founders to develop an online presence solution through building and maintaining their website. Predominantly working with WordPress, Squarespace, and Shopify CMS.

Work Experience

Internal Sales | Amorini Australia | Aug 2021 - Sep 2022

- Managing all custom-made kitchen parts for every order.
- First point of call for customers, communicating to ensure custom products meet specification requirements.
- Improving online portal structures for kitchen sales software.
- Logistics Coordinating stock compiling for orders to be sent to site and between factories, tracking stock holdings and re-orders.
- Data entry using Servicem8 and EQ Business Management Software.

Sales Rep | Camfil Australia (Airepure) | Jun 2018 - Dec 2019

- Building and maintaining customer relations through Sales calls and communication.
- Collaborated with internal engineering teams to provide product and technical advice to customers.
- Improving manufacturing processes, managing customer expectations.
- Reading through tender documents and quoting for projects from mechanical contractors.
- Sales research to secure early sales/tenders.
- Logistics co-ordination, Stock control, re-ordering.
- Data entry using Sage Accpac and Realtime Logistics.

Remedial Therapist | Own Business | Mar 2014 - Jun 2018

- Providing Remedial services to clients
- Business management.
- Point of sale and invoicing using Square.
- Growing and maintaining client base through advertising, networking and social media engagement.
- Appointment tracking using various software products including Power Diarry and Cliniko Practice Management.

Other Roles

Freelance Web Dev | Own Business | Feb 2023 - Present Support Worker | Own Business | March 2023 - Present Mapping operator | Voxel Maps | Jan 2023 - Mar 2023 Cellar hand | Treasure Wine Estates | Jan 2020 - Aug 2021 Delivery Driver | OzHarvest | April 2020 - Oct 2020 Duty Manager | Barossa Rex Centre | Jan 2012 - Aug 2015